<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tenacious Tiger]]></title>
  <link href="http://graphicgraffiti.com.au//atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://graphicgraffiti.com.au//"/>
  <updated>2013-06-12T19:23:55+10:00</updated>
  <id>http://graphicgraffiti.com.au//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Timothy Howard]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
		
	    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shifts & Disillusionment]]></title>
	    <link href="http://graphicgraffiti.com.au//blog/2013/shifts-and-disillusionment/"/>
    
    <updated>2013-05-30T22:56:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://graphicgraffiti.com.au//blog/2013/shifts-and-disillusionment</id>
		
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you even casually follow the circus that is the Australian political system, what would be the first describing words to come out of your mouth? Would you describe it as unstable and erratic, with little variation between the parties? Or would you describe it as a stable and reliable system, with a wide range of choice? If you’re wondering, I currently lean towards the former description. Whilst the beginning of the Labor Government led by Kevin Rudd was fairly stable, with strong public support evident in the “Kevin ‘07” election campaign, the system has been in a continual downfall since Julia Gillard took over the Labor leadership in June 2010.</p>

<p>Question Time, a space supposably reserved for open Q&amp;A on the floor, has become a farce. Politicians continually fight for the media’s attention, using made-up phrases to denounce government policy, rather than to actually question the legislation’s strengths and weaknesses. What’s more, policy is not only attacked, but it is also not uncommon to hear numerous personal insults being directed at individual politicians on both sides of the house. Whilst question time in the past has always been riddled with occasional insults, the past few years have set the bar exceptionally low.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>The thing is, one side will attack the other side’s policy, and then will proceed to advocate for a facsimile policy with very minor changes, just for the chance to paint the opposing policy in a bad light to appease the media, and hope to get a couple more voters on its side. It is pathetic, and overall, childish. Hence, the formally progressive party known as Labor has moved itself to the centre-right of the political spectrum, whilst the conservative party, the Liberal/National Party, has managed to push itself even further to the right. The result is a set of stock-standard policies from the same area of the political spectrum, yet from two apparently different parties, limiting choice. This has had a major effect on the way I view the system today, compared to a few years ago.</p>

<p>If you had asked me what political affiliation I hold back in 2010, I would have said that I supported the Liberal Party, placing myself at the dead centre of the political spectrum. Yet if you ask me now, I’d place myself a quarter-way to the left of the spectrum – a fairly comprehensive change from where I was a couple of years ago. Yet, because there is such limited choice in the current system due to the bundling of the parties to the right, I don’t really have a party who represents my view. The current Labor Government, the so-called progressive party, does not actively support the legalisation of same-sex marriage, whilst controversial subjects such as abortion and euthanasia are placed in the ‘too hard’ pile. Moreover, the current administration has actually just passed $2.3 billion in funding cuts to the tertiary education sector, something that previously would have been practically unthinkable for a progressive party.</p>

<p>From people I have asked, disillusionment with the current state of the system seems to be a pretty common theme – at least within the universities – and its certainly not a good development. Choice promotes political participation, and whilst we don’t have a problem with voter turnout here in Australia due to the implementation of compulsory voting, spikes in the rate of ‘donkey voting’ will be the resulting factor. When a lot of people are disillusioned with the current administration, yet don’t want to support the Liberal Party or minority parties to the far-left, what else is there to do?</p>
]]></content>
		
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
		
	    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Starting from Square One]]></title>
	    <link href="http://graphicgraffiti.com.au//blog/2013/starting-from-square-one/"/>
    
    <updated>2013-05-30T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://graphicgraffiti.com.au//blog/2013/starting-from-square-one</id>
		
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A lot has been happening in my life over the last two and a bit years since I started university, and hence this blog as sat dormant for the most part. Over the last couple of weeks, I have again started writing, and hence I need a place to publish these long-form articles. Hence, I have decided to rejuvenate the weblog for this purpose. I will be publishing my thoughts, which usually cover topics such as African, American, Australian, and Middle Eastern Politics, as well as other areas such as International Law, Technology, Photography, and Culture &amp; Design. Thanks for visiting, and I hope you enjoy the weblog!</p>
]]></content>
		
  </entry>
  
</feed>
