<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tenacious Tiger]]></title>
  <link href="http://graphicgraffiti.com.au//atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://graphicgraffiti.com.au//"/>
  <updated>2012-05-09T21:24:12+10:00</updated>
  <id>http://graphicgraffiti.com.au//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Timothy Howard]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
		
	    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Money, Stress and The Cloud &rarr;]]></title>
	    <link href="http://icelab.com.au/articles/money-stress-and-the-cloud/"/>
    
    <updated>2012-05-07T19:17:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://graphicgraffiti.com.au//blog/2012/tim-riley</id>
		
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Tim Riley&#8217;s post about the way solving a difficult software development problem can interfere with your entire life struck a chord with me. Although Tim&#8217;s problem was bigger than anything I&#8217;ve had to deal with, credit card processing on a client&#8217;s website, the horrible feelings are the same.</p>

<p>All software has bugs, you accept and systematically work through them. But some bugs exist on another plane, unable to be fixed through regular debugging processes. Often they&#8217;re complicated by context, an unfamiliar environment or parts out of your control. You can become <em>obsessed</em> with these bugs. When dealing with them I have an extremely difficult time thinking about anything else. I can&#8217;t read, I can&#8217;t talk to people, I&#8217;m unpleasant to be around. After hours without progress you go to bed thinking about it. Thinking about it makes you angry and frustrated but <em>you can&#8217;t stop thinking about it</em>. You spend so long at the computer you lose all perspective and follow paths that take you further from the solution. With each minute you spend banging your head against the problem you think less clearly and the possibility of solving the problem decreases. It is <em>frustrating</em>.</p>

<p>Experience reminds you how to overcome this wall. You have to get up, leave, distract yourself and come back with a fresh perspective and a clear mind. Actually doing it is difficult because it feels like quitting, it feels like you&#8217;re delaying the solution. It&#8217;s difficult if other people depend on the solution, it&#8217;s difficult because you feel like you&#8217;re close, it&#8217;s difficult because you desperately want it fixed and out of your mind. To solve the problem you have to stop trying to solve the problem, at least for a short while.</p>

<p>Tim went through this while dealing with other external stresses. His post is a great insight for non-programmers on the darker side of software development.</p>
 <a href="http://graphicgraffiti.com.au//blog/2012/tim-riley/">&#9875;</a>]]></content>
		
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
		
	    <title type="html"><![CDATA[No Title]]></title>
	    <link href="http://graphicgraffiti.com.au//blog/2012/microsoft-apple-web/"/>
    
    <updated>2012-02-21T20:35:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://graphicgraffiti.com.au//blog/2012/microsoft-apple-web</id>
		
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve recently been building an HTML email newsletter at work. Getting an HTML email to work across the many <a href="http://www.campaignmonitor.com/css/">extremely limited</a> and broken email clients makes IE6 debugging look like fin. I truly don&#8217;t think HTML email is worth the effort but that&#8217;s another story.</p>

<p>It meant I needed to get a Hotmail account for testing. The first time I&#8217;d used Hotmail in 6 or 7 years. As a regular iCloud webmail user I found what I think is a nice example of the difference between Apple and Microsoft at the screens shown immediately after logging in:</p>

<p><a href="http://static.jimwhimpey.com/blog/hotmail-login-large.png"><img src="http://static.jimwhimpey.com/blog/hotmail-login-small.png" alt="hotmail-login" class="no-border"></a></p>

<p><a href="http://static.jimwhimpey.com/blog/icloud-login-large.png"><img src="http://static.jimwhimpey.com/blog/icloud-login-small.png" alt="icloud-login" class="no-border"></a></p>

<p>I remember as a teenager using Windows before I switched to the Mac getting frustrated about these kinds of UIs and Windows&#8217; inexplicable popularity despite it. It feels great to have watched better persist and <a href="http://www.wolframalpha.com/input/?i=MSFT%2C+AAPL">better eventually win</a>.</p>
]]></content>
		
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
		
	    <title type="html"><![CDATA[From Tumblr to Octopress]]></title>
	    <link href="http://graphicgraffiti.com.au//blog/2012/octopress/"/>
    
    <updated>2012-02-14T20:45:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://graphicgraffiti.com.au//blog/2012/octopress</id>
		
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The move from WordPress to Tumblr a few years ago felt great. All the focus was on posting content and I was liberated from the need to administer a blog. Since then Tumblr has struggled with stability problems while implementing weird &#8220;social features&#8221; like photo replies (but no native text replies) and getting obsessed with things like New York Fashion Week. Recently they added these <a href="http://staff.tumblr.com/post/16980189397/highlighted-posts">dumb labels</a> and I recognised Tumblr is going too far in a direction I&#8217;m not interested in.</p>

<p>I first became interested in (well, aware of) generated flat file publishing systems when I read about Brent&#8217;s <a href="http://inessential.com/2009/01/30/new_publishing_system_tour_of_my_head">homemade system</a> over three years ago. Only a couple of months after that I got a job working on a site that was using a similar flat file system on a <a href="http://www.abc.net.au/news/"><em>much</em> larger scale</a> (it&#8217;s only recently been replaced). I was intrigued by the big advantages of such a system: speed and simplicity.</p>

<p>My loss of respect for Tumblr coincided with reading about <a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a> on <a href="http://mattgemmell.com/2011/09/12/blogging-with-octopress/">Matt Gemmell&#8217;s blog</a>. It sounded perfect. It&#8217;s the kind of new wave of &#8220;hacker&#8221; software that&#8217;s well designed and a joy to use. I credit Github for this great trend.</p>

<h3>Transistion</h3>

<p>Getting my content out of Tumblr was a breeze with Jekyll&#8217;s <a href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/wiki/blog-migrations">blog mirgration script</a>. I had to make a few wholesale modifications to some paths and similar things in the post files the script created but this is where Octopress imediately demonstrated it&#8217;s advantages. I was able to do regex find and replaces across 500+ posts in a few seconds using TextMate. Doing something similar to posts stored in a database would be a real pain in the ass.</p>

<h3>Redesign</h3>

<p>The default Octopress theme is the most elegant default theme shipping with any CMS I&#8217;ve seen but it offers more than I need and in any case, I want a unique look for my blog. The CSS of the default theme is made to be customised and continuing the for hackers ideology its organised into <em>25</em> (yes twenty-five) <a href="http://sass-lang.com/">Sass</a> files which compile down to one CSS file. Every feature of Sass is used, everything is modular, everything is a variable. I was hoping to reuse some of the responsive stuff but it was too complex and I ended up throwing it all out and starting again with my own CSS.</p>

<p>Logic in the template files is handled by <a href="http://liquidmarkup.org/">Liquid</a> which made them easy to modify and generally work with.</p>

<p>When I first started out blogging with WordPress around 8 or 9 years ago I would compulsively redesign my site. Looking back this was fantastic, with every new redesign I&#8217;d learn so much. It might say something about my maturity or current state of mind that even though I&#8217;ve been using this design for over a year and moving to Octopress was an ideal opportunity to change it, I&#8217;ve kept everything the same with only some subtle updates.</p>

<p>I&#8217;d love to create some publicly available Octopress themes just as I did for WordPress and then Tumblr.</p>

<h3>Images</h3>

<p>The only thing missing is a simple way to process images. I need something that I can easily pass through an original, have it resize to a small and a large, upload them to a server somewhere and return some Markdown pointing to the large surrounded by a link to the larger one. I&#8217;ll write a simple script to do this for me and the result will be images decoupled from my publishing system.</p>

<p><strong>Update</strong>: I solved this problem with an <a href="http://valhallaisland.com/blog/2012/octopress-image-resizer/">image resizing script</a>.</p>

<h3>Conclusion</h3>

<p>I&#8217;ve been using Octopress for a week now and I&#8217;ve immediately noticed the blazing speed. I don&#8217;t write much that gets big traffic but I can rest assured know that if I do it&#8217;ll no doubt handle the load with room to spare. Another great advantage is the simple ability to use proper version control for the <em>whole</em> site, both the code that generates it and the generated blog. I love the whole workflow.</p>

<p>While I&#8217;m not publishing with Tumblr anymore I still use it to read the Tumblr blogs I follow. All week I&#8217;ve been seeing <a href="http://cl.ly/3d3C3W2I0l0t1P2X3q1E">this</a> promoted in the dashboard sidebar. It feels like I left just in time.</p>
]]></content>
		
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
		
	    <title type="html"><![CDATA[No Title]]></title>
	    <link href="http://graphicgraffiti.com.au//blog/2012/conventions/"/>
    
    <updated>2012-02-13T21:08:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://graphicgraffiti.com.au//blog/2012/conventions</id>
		
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last week&#8217;s This American Life podcast episode, a rerun from 1997, was all about <a href="http://www.thisamericanlife.org/radio-archives/episode/74/conventions">conventions</a>. At 37:38 starts the saddest story I have ever heard, bizarrely starting at a NeXT convention and a Steve Jobs comedy roast. I&#8217;m not sure why this story hits my usually somewhat callous heart so hard but I was deeply moved.</p>
]]></content>
		
  </entry>
  
</feed>
